Guide to the National Education Association-Committees records, 1857-1996 NEA1003.RG
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Committee on Educational Finance, 1926-1978; Series 3; 3.5 Linear Feet
  - Financial Status of the Public Schools [file 1/3], 1964-1967; series 3 (Box 4347, Folder 6)
  - Financial Status of the Public Schools [file 2/3], 1968-1971; series 3 (Box 4347, Folder 7)
  - Financial Status of the Public Schools [file 3/3], 1972; series 3 (Box 4347, Folder 8)
  - Financing the Changing School Program, 1962; series 3 (Box 4314, Folder 9)
  - Financing Education for Our Changing Population, 1961; series 3 (Box 4314, Folder 10)
  - Financing a National Standard of Education, 1972; Series 3 (Box 4049, Folder 11)
  - The Fiscal Impact of Federal Real Estate...in the Eleven Western States, circa 1951; series 3 (Box 4314, Folder 11)
  - Guides - to the Development of State Finance Programs, undated; series 3 (Box 4314, Folder 12)
  - Guides - to the Improvement of State School Finance Programs, April 1958; series 3 (Box 4314, Folder 13)
  - Immediate Problems in School Finance, No. 1 Hidden Taxes, December 1949; series 3 (Box 4314, Folder 14)
  - Immediate Problems in School Finance, No. 2: School Finance Problems, January 1950; series 3 (Box 4314, Folder 15)
  - The Index of Local Economic Ability in State School Finance Programs: A Review of the Theory and Practice in the Use of Measures of Local Taxpaying Ability based upon Economic Indexes, October 1953; series 3 (Box 4314, Folder 16)
  - Inventory of Public School Expenditures, 1946-1948; Series 3 (Box 4049, Folder 12)
  - Legal Provisions for Summer Schools, 1964; Series 3 (Box 4008, Folder 2)
  - Long-Range Planning in School Fiance, 1963; series 3 (Box 4314, Folder 17)
  - Memoranda, 1965; Series 3 (Box 1156, Folder 6)
  - Military Policy and Budget Priorities - Fiscal Years 1979-82, 1978; Series 3 (Box 4008, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1958-1959; Series 3 (Box 1157, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1960-1965; Series 3 (Box 1157, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1967-1975; Series 3 (Box 1157, Folder 3)
  - NEA's Federal Finance Study, February 1978; Series 3 (Box 4049, Folder 13)
  - New Directions in Financing Public Schools, 1960; series 3 (Box 4314, Folder 18)
  - New Local Sources of Tax Revenue, October, 1959; Series 3 (Box 4008, Folder 4)
  - New Sources of Local Revenues for Public Schools, May 1950; series 3 (Box 4314, Folder 19)
  - Nine State Taxes: Rates and Collections, January, 1961; Series 3 (Box 4008, Folder 5)
  - Payments in Lieu of Taxes on Federally Owned Real Estate, April 1947; series 3 (Box 4314, Folder 20)
  - Price Tag for Toby: Speaker's Guide and Script, May, 1963; Series 3 (Box 4008, Folder 6)
  - Problems and Opportunities in Financing Education, 1959; series 3 (Box 4315, Folder 1)
  - Proceedings of the National Conference on School Finance Problems May 22-23, 1958, circa 1958; series 3 (Box 4315, Folder 2)
  - Proceedings of Western States Conference on Public Lands and the Financing of Education, 1946; Series 3 (Box 4060, Folder 7)
  - Proceedings - School Finance Conference, April 3-4, 1942; Series 3 (Box 4060, Folder 8)
  - Professional Salaries for Professional Teachers, 1958-1961; series 3 (Box 4315, Folder 3)
  - Professional Salaries for Professional Teachers, February, 1961; Series 3 (Box 4008, Folder 7)
  - Public Opionion Polls on American Education, May 1958; series 3 (Box 4315, Folder 4)
  - Public-School Finance: A Unit of Work, May 1953; series 3 (Box 4315, Folder 5)
  - Publications Lists, undated; series 3 (Box 4383, Folder 14)
  - Relation of Federal and State Public Lands to School Finance, 1941; Series 3 (Box 4060, Folder 9)
  - A Report of How [State] Citizens Feel About Federal Aid to Public Schools, 1960; Series 3 (Box 4049, Folder 14)
  - Report of the Tenure Committee of One Hundred of the NEA, July 1928; Series 3 (Box 4629, Folder 3)
  - Revenue-sharing, 1970; Series 3 (Box 3303, Folder 2)
  - "School Finance Situations" (by State), January 1947; Series 3 (Box 1157, Folder 4)
  - "School Finance Systems", 1934-1938; Series 3 (Box 1157, Folder 5)
  - "School Finance Systems" (Revised, 1941-1942), Series 3 (Box 1157, Folder 6)
  - School Finance Systems Statements, 1946-1948; Series 3 (Box 1157, Folder 7)
  - School Finance Systems Statements, 1948-1950; Series 3 (Box 1157, Folder 8)
  - School Finance Systems Statements, 1949-1953; Series 3 (Box 1157, Folder 9)
  - School Finance Systems Statements, 1951-1953; Series 3 (Box 1157, Folder 10)
  - School Finance Systems Statements, 1953-1955; Series 3 (Box 1157, Folder 11)
  - School Finance Systems Statements, 1954-1956; Series 3 (Box 1157, Folder 12)
  - School Revenues in the War Emergency, May 1942; series 3 (Box 4315, Folder 6)
  - Severance Taxation of Natural Resources, July 1950; series 3 (Box 4315, Folder 7)
  - So That You May Know About Financing Public Schools, 1965; Series 3 (Box 4008, Folder 8)
  - Southern and Midwestern Regional Conference on School Finance, 1941-1942; series 3 (Box 4315, Folder 8)
  - Speaker's Guide and Script: Price Tag for Toby, May 1963; series 3 (Box 4400, Folder 9)
  - State Taxes in 1967, January, 1969; Series 3 (Box 4008, Folder 9)
  - State Taxes in 1968, July, 1969; Series 3 (Box 4008, Folder 10)
  - State White House Conferences Discuss School Finance Problems, April 1957; series 3 (Box 4315, Folder 9)
  - Statistical Tables to Accompany Extent of Schooling of the Rural-Farm Population and the Urban Population, November 1944; series 3 (Box 4315, Folder 10)
  - Status and Fiscal Significance of Federal Lands in Eleven Western States, October 1950; series 3 (Box 4315, Folder 11)
  - A Study of the Public Attitudes Toward Financing Public Schools, July 1974; Series 3 (Box 4061, Folder 1)
  - Tax Education and School Finance, February 1941-May 1952; series 3 (Box 4315, Folder 12)
  - Tax Limitation Laws, 1948-1965; series 3 (Box 4315, Folder 13)
  - Tax Losses from Property Tax Exemptions: A Pilot Study Based on the State of Michigan, March 1954; series 3 (Box 4315, Folder 14)
  - Tax Revenues of Public Schools, 1949-50, September 1952; series 3 (Box 4316, Folder 1)
  - [Tax and School Finance Pamphlets], 1959; Series 3 (Box 4047, Folder 3)
  - Taxes are Good, March, 1961; Series 3 (Box 4008, Folder 11)
  - Taxes Contribute to Progress, May, 1960; Series 3 (Box 4008, Folder 12)
  - Unfinished Business, 1946-1948; Series 3 (Box 4061, Folder 2)
  - Valuation of Property, July, 1969; Series 3 (Box 4008, Folder 13)
  - Valuation of Property: Assessments and Sales Prices Compared, January 1959; series 3 (Box 4316, Folder 2)
- Committee on International Relations, 1933-1983; Series 4; 3 Linear Feet
  Series contains materials created within the Committee on International Relations. The files largely include reports and brochures.
  The Committee on International Relations was established in 1920. The committee was formed to help with educational exchange activities, to work with the UNESCO National Commission, to prepare information kits on world affairs, and to maintain a liaison with other interested groups in education and world affairs. The committee was dissolved in 1972.
  - 1980 World Confederation of Organizations of the Teaching Professions Assembly Resolutions, December 1980; series 4 (Box 4347, Folder 9)
  - About UNESCO, June 1954; series 4 (Box 4347, Folder 10)
  - Activities Planned for International Education Year, circa 1970; series 4 (Box 4347, Folder 11)
  - American Dissertations on Foreign Education, 1959; Series 4 (Box 4629, Folder 4)
  - Bibliographies, 1947-1948; series 4 (Box 4347, Folder 12)
  - Box Score on the UN, 1954-1955; series 4 (Box 4400, Folder 10)
  - British Mini-Exchanges, December 20 1979 - December 21 1979; series 4 (Box 4493, Folder 3)
  - Brochures-Conference on International Relations, July 1950; Series 4 (Box 1158, Folder 1)
  - Brochures-Hemisphere Conference of the World Federation of Education Associations, December 1940; Series 4 (Box 1158, Folder 2)
  - Brochures-"Toward World Understanding", circa 1939; Series 4 (Box 1158, Folder 3)
  - Chairmen of International Relations Committees in NEA Departments, circa 1956; series 4 (Box 4347, Folder 13)
  - Christmas Throughout the World: A Selected Bibliography of Plays, Stories, Films and Recordings of Christmas and Christmans Customs in Many Lands, October 1950; series 4 (Box 4347, Folder 14)
  - Committee on International Relations Brochure, undated; series 4 (Box 4347, Folder 15)
  - Committee Recommendations 1981-82, circa 1981; series 4 (Box 4347, Folder 16)
  - Cultural Values: Eastern and Western, 1959; series 4 (Box 4316, Folder 3)
  - Day at the United Nations, 1961; series 4 (Box 4348, Folder 1)
  - Discussion Guides (Produced at Lindenwood College), July 1950; Series 4 (Box 1158, Folder 4)
  - Dr. Ben M. Cherrington "Education for International Understanding " Revised Draft, Undated; series 4 (Box 4348, Folder 2)
  - The Educational International Insider, 1998; series 4 (Box 4419, Folder 1)
  - Education for International Security, September 1943; series 4 (Box 4348, Folder 3)
  - Education for International Understanding in American Schools: Suggestions and Readings, June 1948; series 4 (Box 4348, Folder 4)
  - Education for International Understanding: Preliminary Draft, July 1947; series 4 (Box 4348, Folder 5)
  - Final Report: International Relations Study Project, 1944; series 4 (Box 4348, Folder 6)
  - Foreign Employment Opportunities for U.S. Teachers, circa 1948; series 4 (Box 4348, Folder 7)
  - Guide to Teaching about the United Nations and World Affairs, 1953-1955; series 4 (Box 4316, Folder 4)
  - Guide to Teaching about the United Nations and World Affairs: A Teachers' Handbook, 1953; series 4 (Box 4348, Folder 8)
  - Handbooks on United Nations, 1946 - 1951; series 4 (Box 4316, Folder 5)
  - How Peoples Work Together...The United Nations and the Specialized Agencies, circa 1952; series 4 (Box 4348, Folder 9)
  - The Interdependent, January/ February 1983; series 4 (Box 4348, Folder 10)
  - International Aspects of Human Rights: A Handbook, May 1950; series 4 (Box 4348, Folder 11)
  - International Health Activities and the School: A Report on the Activities of Four United Nations Agencies Relating to Health Education, Disease Control and Health Services, 1960; series 4 (Box 4348, Folder 12)
  - International Relations Clubs Bulletins, 1948; series 4 (Box 4348, Folder 13)
  - International Relations Committee in NEA Journal Volume 32, Number 1: January 1943, series 4 (Box 4348, Folder 14)
  - International Relations: Services and Activities of 174 Organizations, June 1939; series 4 (Box 4348, Folder 15)
  - International Understanding: Catalogue of 16 MM Films Dealing with the United Nations, Its Member States and Related Subjects, 1950; series 4 (Box 4316, Folder 6)
  - "It Decorates...Most Flowerly" The Korean Chapter in the Story of the NEA Overseas Teacher Fund, 1956; series 4 (Box 4316, Folder 7)
  - January Meeting, February 1981; series 4 (Box 4348, Folder 16)
  - The Lindenwood Conference on International Relations: A Report on an Experiment in International Understanding for Classroom Teachers, Ca. 1948; Series 4 (Box 4040, Folder 3)
  - Local and State Affiliate Involvement in International Relations Programs: Possible Activities, Undated; series 4 (Box 4348, Folder 17)
  - Making Victory Secure, June 1944; series 4 (Box 4316, Folder 8)
  - Making Victory Secure, June 1944; series 4 (Box 4348, Folder 18)
  - Marks of the World-Minded American, undated; series 4 (Box 4348, Folder 19)
  - Memoranda, 1950-1958; Series 4 (Box 1158, Folder 5)
  - Memorandum re: International Education Year, October 1969; series 4 (Box 4348, Folder 20)
  - Memorandums, 1969, 1979; series 4 (Box 4349, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1942-1957; Series 4 (Box 1158, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, March 1979 - March 1980; series 4 (Box 4493, Folder 4)
  - NEA International Relations Caucus Form Sheet, undated; series 4 (Box 4349, Folder 2)
  - The NEA Overseas Teach Corps: 1967 Vietnam Officials of Ministry of Education U.S. Observation Tour, series 4 (Box 4349, Folder 3)
  - The NEA Overseas Teach Corps Brochures, circa 1963; series 4 (Box 4349, Folder 4)
  - Newsletter, 1958-1959; series 4 (Box 4316, Folder 9)
  - Newsletter-"International Relations", December 1982; Series 4 (Box 1158, Folder 7)
  - Nicaragua: An On-Sight Report, circa 1983; series 4 (Box 4349, Folder 5)
  - Notes on the International Trade Organization, circa 1946; series 4 (Box 4349, Folder 6)
  - One World, Two Missions, undated; series 4 (Box 4349, Folder 7)
  - Organizations and Government Agencies Engaged in Teacher and Student Exchange Activities and Some Current Magazine Articles on Teacher and Student Exchange, January 1948; series 4 (Box 4349, Folder 8)
  - Other Lands Other Peoples [file 1/6], 1960; series 4 (Box 4349, Folder 9)
  - Other Lands Other Peoples [file 2/6], 1962; series 4 (Box 4349, Folder 10)
  - Other Lands Other Peoples [file 3/6], 1962; series 4 (Box 4349, Folder 11)
  - Other Lands Other Peoples [file 4/6], 1964; series 4 (Box 4349, Folder 12)
  - Other Lands Other Peoples [file 5/6], 1964; series 4 (Box 4349, Folder 13)
  - Other Lands Other Peoples [file 6/6], 1967; series 4 (Box 4349, Folder 14)
  - Pocono Manor Conference, 1947; series 4 (Box 4350, Folder 1)
  - Promoting Co-operation and Goodwill through Education, 1938-1940; series 4 (Box 4316, Folder 10)
  - Promoting International Cooperation Thru Education, June 1938; series 4 (Box 4350, Folder 2)
  - Promoting World Goodwill in High Schools and Thru the Activities of Tearchers Organization, 1940; series 4 (Box 4350, Folder 3)
  - Questions and Answers about UNESCO, 1957; series 4 (Box 4350, Folder 4)
  - Recommendations of Committee on International Relations, 1977-1979; series 4 (Box 4350, Folder 5)
  - Replies Received in Response to Dr. Cherrington's Letter Asking: " What Should Be Taught by American Schools about International Affairs?" 1946-1947, series 4 (Box 4350, Folder 6)
  - Report of the 1975 NEA Delegation to the Union of Societ Socialist Republics, series 4 (Box 4350, Folder 7)
  - Report on Adoption and Sponsorship of War Orphans, July 1947; series 4 (Box 4350, Folder 8)
  - Report of the Committee on International Relations, 1933-1934; series 4 (Box 4350, Folder 9)
  - Report of the NEA Delegation Visit to Israel as Guest of the Israel Teachers Union, circa 1975; series 4 (Box 4350, Folder 10)
  - Report on the Questionnaire Concerning International Relations Activities, circa 1956; series 4 (Box 4350, Folder 11)
  - Reports-UN Conference, March 1957; Series 4 (Box 1158, Folder 14)
  - Report of the USAID/NESA Programmed Learning Feasibility Study, 1970; series 4 (Box 4350, Folder 12)
  - Reports-"Box Score on the UN", 1955; Series 4 (Box 1158, Folder 8)
  - Reports-"Educational Investment in the Pacific Community", March 1963; Series 4 (Box 1158, Folder 9)
  - Reports-Fourth National Conference on International Social and Economic Development, March 1957; Series 4 (Box 1158, Folder 10)
  - Reports-"International Understanding, Catalogue of 16mm Films", 1950; Series 4 (Box 1158, Folder 11)
  - Reports-"The Lindenwood Conference on International Relations", June 1950; Series 4 (Box 1158, Folder 12)
  - Reports-"The Meaning of International Understanding for the Teacher", October 1956; Series 4 (Box 1158, Folder 13)
  - Reports-"The World Health Organization Observes Tenth Anniversary", June 1958; Series 4 (Box 1158, Folder 15)
  - A Selected and Annotated Bibliography of Resource Materials for Teaching about the United Nations, circa 1958; series 4 (Box 4316, Folder 11)
  - Services and Activities of 174 Organizations, 1939; series 4 (Box 4316, Folder 12)
  - SIFT on World Affairs - Newsletters, 1957-1958; series 4 (Box 4316, Folder 13)
  - Some Foreign Study Opportunities for U.S. Teachers and Students, circa 1949; series 4 (Box 4350, Folder 13)
  - Some Things to Do, April 1943; series 4 (Box 4350, Folder 14)
  - Soviet Education and the New Soviet Man, February 1962; series 4 (Box 4350, Folder 15)
  - Staff Newsletter to the Committee on International Relations, January 1957; series 4 (Box 4350, Folder 16)
  - Statement of the NEA for the House Subcommittee on International Relations on Programs for International Education, July 1978; series 4 (Box 4350, Folder 17)
  - Teacher Exchange and Study Abroad Existing Opportunities..., May 1979; series 4 (Box 4350, Folder 18)
  - Teachers on Exchange in U.S. from Great Britain, Canada, France 1948-49, November 1948; series 4 (Box 4350, Folder 19)
  - Teachers Handbook for United Nations Day and Week, 1951; series 4 (Box 4350, Folder 20)
  - Teaching United Nations: A Pictorial Repost, 1949; series 4 (Box 4316, Folder 14)
  - Timeline of Events, undated; series 4 (Box 4350, Folder 21)
  - United Nations Box Score, 1953-1954; series 4 (Box 4316, Folder 15)
  - United Nations Pamphlets, 1956-1970; 1956-1958; series 4 (Box 4350, Folder 22)
  - The U.S. Academy of Peace, circa 1981; series 4 (Box 4350, Folder 23)
  - UNESCO Packet, February 1952; series 4 (Box 4380, Folder 1)
    Separated Items Note
  - Unusual Teaching Opportunities at Home and Abroad, undated; series 4 (Box 4350, Folder 24)
  - WCOTP/ International Relations, 1982-1983; series 4 (Box 4350, Folder 25)
  - Your Handbook on Current International Issues: To Accompany the International Relations Study Kit, 1945-1946; series 4 (Box 4350, Folder 26)
- Committee on Planning and Organizational Development, 1887-1985; 1968-1978; Series 5; 17 Linear Feet
  The planned Constitutional Convention in the early 1970s led to the creation of four committees including the Committee on Planning and Organizational Development (CPOD).
  The CPOD was created in 1969 to consider what school conditions would be like in 5, 10, or more years in the future and the programs that would be needed. These expectations would help shape the revision of the constitution to ensure its applicability in the years ahead.
  After the convention and the need for the projections waned, the committee was disbanded in 1975.
  Series contains materials created within the Committee on Planning and Organizational Development. The files include agenda books, memorandum, correspondence, and meeting minutes.
  The files cover a multitude of issues relating to the operations of the NEA and its structure. Issues covered include the budget, dues increases, local-state-national relationships, the Critical Issues Conference and relationships with other organizations.
  - 21st Century Teachers Info and Color Log WP 6.1, 1996; Series 5 (Box 4033, Floppy disk 2)
  - Accountability, 1970-1971; Series 5 (Box 1159, Folder 1)
  - Accountability, 1974; Series 5 (Box 1159, Folder 2)
  - Accounting, April 1973; Series 5 (Box 1159, Folder 3)
  - Activity Reports-Nicktash, Helen, 1976-1977; Series 5 (Box 1159, Folder 4)
    Niktash, Helen
  - Ad Hoc Committee on the Rights of Students, September 1969; Series 5 (Box 1159, Folder 5)
  - Ad Hoc Committee to Design a Membership Campaign Proposal, May 1969; Series 5 (Box 1159, Folder 6)
  - Administrative Memoranda, 1975; Series 5 (Box 1159, Folder 7)
  - Administrative Procedures-Constitution and Bylaws, 1974; Series 5 (Box 1159, Folder 8)
  - Adult Education Service-"The Program of the Division of...", February 1970-June 1970; Series 5 (Box 1159, Folder 9)
  - Advisory Council Meeting, 1972-1973; Series 5 (Box 1159, Folder 10)
  - Affiliate Relations Committee, 1975; Series 5 (Box 1159, Folder 11)
  - Affiliation/Merger, June 1972; Series 5 (Box 1159, Folder 12)
  - Affiliation Process, 1974; Series 5 (Box 1159, Folder 13)
  - Affiliation Standards, 1976; Series 5 (Box 1159, Folder 14)
  - Affirmative Action-Current Status, 1975-1976; Series 5 (Box 1159, Folder 15)
  - Agenda Book, November 1968; Series 5 (Box 1160, Folder 1)
  - Agenda Book, November 1968; Series 5 (Box 1160, Folder 2)
  - Agenda Book, January 1969; Series 5 (Box 1160, Folder 3)
  - Agenda Book, April 1969; Series 5 (Box 1160, Folder 4)
  - Agenda Book, April 1969; Series 5 (Box 1160, Folder 5)
  - Agenda Book, August 1969; Series 5 (Box 1160, Folder 6)
  - Agenda Book, August 1969; Series 5 (Box 1160, Folder 7)
  - Agenda Book, November 1969; Series 5 (Box 1161, Folder 1)
  - Agenda Book, November 1969; Series 5 (Box 1161, Folder 2)
  - Agenda Book, November 1969; Series 5 (Box 1161, Folder 3)
  - Agenda Book, January 1970; Series 5 (Box 1161, Folder 4)
  - Agenda Book, January 1970; Series 5 (Box 1161, Folder 5)
  - Agenda Book, March 1970; Series 5 (Box 1161, Folder 6)
  - Agenda Book, March 1970; Series 5 (Box 1162, Folder 1)
  - Agenda Book, May 1970; Series 5 (Box 1162, Folder 2)
  - Agenda Book, May 1970; Series 5 (Box 1162, Folder 3)
  - Agenda Book, July 1970; Series 5 (Box 1162, Folder 4)
  - Agenda Book, July 1970; Series 5 (Box 1162, Folder 5)
  - Agenda Book, October 1970; Series 5 (Box 1162, Folder 6)
  - Agenda Book, October 1970; Series 5 (Box 1162, Folder 7)
  - Agenda Book, December 1970; Series 5 (Box 1163, Folder 1)
  - Agenda Book, December 1970; Series 5 (Box 1163, Folder 2)
  - Agenda Book, May 1971; Series 5 (Box 1163, Folder 3)
  - Agenda Book, October 1971; Series 5 (Box 1163, Folder 4)
  - Agenda Book, December 1971; Series 5 (Box 1163, Folder 5)
  - Agenda Book, December 1971; Series 5 (Box 1163, Folder 6)
  - Agenda Book, January 1972; Series 5 (Box 1163, Folder 7)
  - Agenda Book, April 1972; Series 5 (Box 1163, Folder 8)
  - Agenda Book, October 1972; Series 5 (Box 1163, Folder 9)
  - Agenda Book, December 1972; Series 5 (Box 1164, Folder 1)
  - Agenda Book, February 1973; Series 5 (Box 1164, Folder 2)
  - Agenda Book, March 1973; Series 5 (Box 1164, Folder 3)
  - Agenda Book, April 1973; Series 5 (Box 1164, Folder 4)
  - Agenda Book, May 1973; Series 5 (Box 1164, Folder 5)
  - Agenda Book, October 1973; Series 5 (Box 1164, Folder 6)
  - Agenda Book, January 1974; Series 5 (Box 1164, Folder 7)
  - Agenda Book, February 1974; Series 5 (Box 1165, Folder 1)
  - Agenda Book, March 1974; Series 5 (Box 1165, Folder 2)
  - Agenda Book, October 1974; Series 5 (Box 1165, Folder 3)
  - Agenda Book, January 1975; Series 5 (Box 1165, Folder 4)
  - Agenda Book, April 1975; Series 5 (Box 1165, Folder 5)
  - Agendas, November 1968-March 1974; Series 5 (Box 1586, Folder 1)
  - American Association of School Administrators (AASA), 1974; Series 5 (Box 1165, Folder 6)
  - American Association of University Professors, 1971-1973; Series 5 (Box 1165, Folder 7)
  - American Association of University Professors, 1974; Series 5 (Box 1165, Folder 8)
  - AFL-CIO, November 1971-December 1971; Series 5 (Box 1165, Folder 9)
  - American Federation of Teachers [file 1/3], 1966-1972; Series 5 (Box 1165, Folder 10)
  - American Federation of Teachers [file 2/3], 1966-1972; Series 5 (Box 1166, Folder 1)
  - American Federation of Teachers [file 3/3], 1966-1972; Series 5 (Box 1166, Folder 2)
  - American Federation of Teachers-Reports on Conventions, 1974-1976; Series 5 (Box 1166, Folder 3)
  - "Analyses of Membership Possibilities", December 1970; Series 5 (Box 1166, Folder 4)
  - Analysis of Constitution and By-laws (Original), circa 1973; Series 5 (Box 1166, Folder 5)
  - "Analysis of the Documents Developed at the July 1971 Constitutional Convention of the National Education Association of the United States", circa 1971; Series 5 (Box 1166, Folder 6)
  - "An Analysis of NEA Membership, Revenue and Expenditures, Past and Projected", November 1974; Series 5 (Box 1166, Folder 7)
  - An Analysis of Possible NEA Dues Increase, June 1974; Series 5 (Box 1166, Folder 8)
  - Annual Meeting, June 1974; Series 5 (Box 1166, Folder 9)
  - Annual Meeting, July 1975; Series 5 (Box 1166, Folder 10)
  - Annual Meeting (Minneapolis), 1977; Series 5 (Box 1167, Folder 1)